Fixed & Synced by bozxphd. Enjoy The Flick.
- Why?
- So we can have a record of it,
so we can show Papi.
It helps him to remember.
Now, are you ready?
Like we practiced, okay?
- Like that?
- Si, exactly like that.
Now don't stop, okay, Annie?
- This should be take 11.
This Ana Carter, U.S. citizen,
documenting proof
for my student visa.
Phd chemical engineering
at Oxford university.
Currently testing electrolyte
for batteries exposed
to varying
electromagnetic pulse.
7.13, electromagnetic
pulse managed
by algorithm 13, running 13.
Hypothesis correct, atom again
unaffected by varying pulse.
Electrolyte stable,
7.13 successful.
Test 7.14, electromagnetic
pulse managed by algorithm 14.
And we're running 14.
Okay, hypothesis correct.
Atom unaffected by varying
pulse, electrolyte stable.
7.14 successful.
Test 7 and 15.
Pulse managed by algorithm 15.
Running 15.
Hypothesis correct, atom
unaffected by varying pulse.
Electrolyte stable,
7.15 successful.
Test 7.16, electromagnetic
pulse managed
by digital algorithm 16.
Running 16.
Hypothesis correct, atom
unaffected by varying pulse.
Electrolyte stable,
16 successful.
Test 7.17, pulse managed
by digital algorithm 17.
Running 17.
Whoa.
What?
- Hey, I'm gonna take my
undergrads for a beer.
Do you want to come?
- Yep, it happened again.
Disappeared.
- It doesn't make sense.
- Coffee?
I brought some good stuff.
- Six times now,
it's always the same.
- So?
- So, it's not a mistake.
We're making this happen.
- Deconstruct.
- An atom disappeared.
- Just an electron.
- Disappeared, so deconstruct.
An electron can't just vanish.
- Theoretically, if it's destroyed,
or moved, or hiding, it can.
- We haven't destroyed anything.
If you had you
would wiped out...
Okay, so you removed
it or it's hidden.
- But carbon wouldn't have
bonded if the electron
- was just hiding.
- So you removed it.
Okay.
I've just never seen it
done like that before.
Where's it going and how?
And this is gonna work?
- The calculations are proportional
to the subject volume.
For an atom this should be fine.
- Where did you get it?
- The algorithm, I mean.
- I wasn't even
testing algorithms.
I was trying to show variance in pulse
had no effect on the electrolyte.
- Wait, but hang on a sec.
- Where's this one from?
- Test 17
to effect an entire atom.
No hypothesis.
No hypothesis, running 17.
- We're gonna need
a bigger boat.
Okay, so these I recognize
from my undergrad days.
This is just secondary
school geometry.
But 17, it's quantum theory.
Except you've Dicked
around with it.
Why have you got pi in there?
- I needed an endless
string, non-repeating.
- Yeah, but you
can't use pi this way.
It doesn't make sense.
- I'm gonna try a molecule.
- You're gonna crash the server.
- We need help.
A molecule is
something I can trace,
but we need help recoding
so we use less power.
- If you're talking
about that...
- Can you ask her?
- Fuck no, she's like...
Seriously, no.
- Distributive computing, mostly
it's charities that use it.
You sign your computer up to
kill cancer in its spare time,
your processor crunches
numbers whilst you sleep.
- This place runs a couple.
- Really?
- Really.
- Can we use them?
- You've cut your hair, Nathan.
Sure, you register your
project, give it a year,
hope a dozen people log on.
I like it.
You look a little less faggy.
- Distributive computing...
- Needs volunteers.
- We need a lot.
- How many?
- Our test crashed the server.
- I heard, well done!
You hackers, you.
- We need processing on
the Petaflop's range.
- What are you doing up there?
- And this could pull that?
- It's not legal,
it won't happen like that.
- But it is possible?
- Tapping the school's easy,
we're inside the firewall.
Likewise, a worm that will
sign people up to the grid
without their knowledge,
piece of piss.
But how the worm spreads.
It could fizzle in a week,
or you could have
half the planet
donating spare
capacity by Tuesday.
- That would be nice.
- Here.
- Hello.
- Vivisection is murder.
- Okay, Scrufter.
- And you can do this?
- Sure.
Tell me what you're doing.
I want in.
- Ana, what she's
suggesting is illegal.
Hacking, stealing servers.
Okay, let's do it.
- And their packing, it's all...
- it'll be fine.
It's just, it makes me sad.
Something nice?
- Si, actually it's grilled
chicken wrapped in parma ham
stuffed with
mozzarella and basil.
Si, I know.
I know.
- Nathan, you're
such a goddamn wet.
It's utterly untraceable.
It just worms along from email
address book to address book
feeding us power, and it's
growing exponentially.
I'm monitoring Norton, Mcafee,
but so far we're clean.
God, this fucker's heavy.
- Come watch.
Three, two, one.
- Okay.
Technically, we're not
moving stuff, are we?
Moving involves locomotion.
- We know we're not destroying.
- Or deconstituting.
There's no residue, no
trace of the particle.
- It means we're
sending it somewhere.
- Yeah, but where?
- The field equation implies
- we're creating a frame.
- And we have marble 42.
- Again, I see what we're doing.
- Just not how.
And these variables, Ana,
this part of the equation?
- And goodbye, marble.
Oh, yeah, feedback from
the electrodes, current.
I had to account for it.
- So a number comes back in fed
into the equation from outside?
- An electric oscillation, yes.
- So, those are the electrodes?
- And marble 44.
- An end can be...
- negative.
And your electrodes,
they were right angles.
- Adios, marble 44.
Yeah, so?
- Your electrodes
create three axes.
- In three dimensions.
I never noticed before because
you have them pointing up.
- But instead of like this,
you define them like this.
- Giving you an X,
y, and a Z axis.
- Up and down, forward
and back, left and right.
Relative to the node...
- we could mark
a point anywhere.
- Literally, anywhere.
- Using the dimensions of the
subjects to define the unit.
- Test 17.108 to
control the out node.
Running diagnostics.
So, if we wanted to send...
- can we settle on something
with a touch of panache?
Phase, teleport, zap?
You lack imagination.
- Okay, we want
to phase it here.
- What's that?
40 centimeters on
the positive X axis?
- Yeah, put a little
into the y, negative,
so that we can see that
these things will work.
- So X is 40, call
it eight units.
Negative one y,
negative two on the Z.
Hypothesis has the
subject moving, phasing,
to a location 40
centimeters away.
- And landing with a bump.
Running 17.108.
- Whoa.
- Are you fucking joking?
- Oh, my god, we did it.
- Not yet.
We still have a range
more test to run,
- but you know what we've done.
- Funding.
Funding, funding,
we need to raise...
- the worm is giving
us the capacity.
- Everything will change.
- Everything.
Look at the
implications, just think.
- Look, my uncle is a fund
manager, I could call him.
- Everything,
I mean, the obvious.
- Can we make it stable?
- Not subject to
flying, but intrinsic?
- It wouldn't stay open.
- Permanently, no.
The processor
wouldn't handle it.
- You're saying
to create a space?
- A sphere.
- It would be a sphere,
there's no other way.
- Everything will change,
start with the obvious.
- With a predetermined out node.
- It's wormhole theory, we've...
- Built a wormhole.
A wormhole.
We're teleporting shit?
People, we're going to be gods.
GPS will be up tomorrow.
- Dad, can you call Lawrence?
- We need solicitors.
- Start with the obvious.
Patents, patents, copyrights.
- We need experts, yes.
But we need them soon.
And uncle Scott, tell
them we'll have a demo.
- In a month?
- In a week?
- On Friday.
- Look, dad, I've got to go.
But what this is, is big.
- So medicine.
Tumors out of the
brain like that.
Think how agriculture
will change.
From a wormhole on a farm,
zap, into your fridge.
The way we feed the
world will change.
Wormholes in the floodplains
of Bangladesh and the Sahara
will bloom energy.
- If this works and it doesn't
collapse all of reality.
- We open wormholes
to the earth's core,
tap geothermal energy,
run cables through wormholes
to solar panels near the sun.
- We'll need to check
for cellular mutation
or molecular decay.
- We also need to
discuss structure.
We need to set up a
company, we need finance.
- Minerals, we can pull
minerals from anywhere,
send products everywhere.
- Liv, where's this one going?
- Gods, we're gonna
change the world.
Hello, ferny.
Oh my god!
Aw, your face.
- What, what did I do?
- Thank you.
- You're chewing a toothpick.
- It's what cool guys do.
- Oh, so you're a cool guy now?
- Yeah, I am, actually.
- Wanna see a magic trick?
- Yeah.
- I can make matter disappear.
- Oh, can you now?
- Mhmm.
You ready?
Alright.
You watching?
- Yeah.
- Good.
Ah,
okay.
One more time, okay?
- Good.
- I'm watching you.
- I know.
Shit!
I used to be able to do this.
- I think you should
probably stick to the piano.
- Oh, thank you.
Ha!
- Very good.
- I know.
- But where did it go?
Up your sleeve.
- Really?
- You messed up the first two
times on purpose, didn't you?
So the third time I
wasn't paying attention
and you picked it up
with your other hand.
Show me.
Show me!
Yes, I'm a genius.
Six years since we were
undergrads together.
- Second year physics.
- Long time.
- It is.
Nate?
Tests are perfect.
DNA, RNA identical.
Hey!
Looking good.
- Yeah, I warned you
I was a cool guy.
Come see, Liv's created
a stable sphere.
- It's only 30
centimeters across.
We can't process
anything bigger, not yet.
Tempting, right?
- It's so interesting.
It doesn't look like
I thought it would.
- No, it's doing...
You can see the numbers there.
It's doing things
with light that...
Anyway, stand over there.
Yeah.
Phase attack!
Get in.
- That is something, though.
There's potential for it.
- No one will attack
anyone, hippie.
Retaliation would be too easy.
- Like the atom bomb?
- Bingo.
Think how this will
affect transport.
- If we can phase live fauna.
- Think.
- Cities will change.
People will live in the
country, phase into the office.
- All the social
problems cities bring...
- will change.
- Travel will change.
Phase to the mountains.
- Phase to the beaches,
to mom for tea.
- To the moon.
To the vault of
a bank, anywhere.
- Now you're talking.
Nathan.
Such wit.
We're moving fast here.
- You think we should...
- no.
No, we need to get a test in
before the university
get involved.
Buying all the hardware
to run this legally
means serious product first.
- Okay, stinky thing.
Prepare to make history.
Granny?
Hello, granny, it's Liv.
Olivia.
Yes.
Question, how's tinkles?
- Yeah, the patents.
I need them processed.
I needed them
processed yesterday
and I need them done
in Ana's name, okay?
All of them, they're all
gonna want to see this.
I mean, dad, this is massive.
Just support me once.
- Your
grandmother's cat, really?
- Fuck, oh my god!
- Way bigger.
Dad, it's like
inventing electricity.
- It's sound science.
Granny will spot anything odd.
Nate, can you give
us a hand here?
- It's all possible, isn't it?
- This is the
single biggest thing
- that mankind...
- little boy a hand.
- Will ever have done.
- Red suits you, and
this thing with the hair?
No, really, I like it, honest.
It's not so dragon tattoo,
hacker stock image.
- It's a good move.
Incognito.
- Olivia, darling.
Come in, come in!
Oh, it's cold out there.
Oh, come in, come on through.
Well you look lovely.
You've taken that horrible
blue shit out of your hair.
Are you, um, here
for tinkles again?
- Hello to you too, granny.
No, no.
We just wanted to see
how he's doing, actually.
- Well, he's doing wonderfully.
Hello there, I'm Brenda.
I'm Olivia's
grandmother, and you are?
- I'm Ana, hi.
This is Nathan.
- I'm Nathan.
- They're my assistants.
Although Ana is an immigrant,
so feel free to
call border patrol.
Tinkles is fine?
- You're not being
suspicious at all.
Any reason why he wouldn't be?
- Oh, he fractured the
space time continuum,
- visited the fourth dimension.
- Did he now?
Would you like some tea?
- This place is nuts.
- Tell me about it.
I knew she came from
money, but this?
- You're looking
quite smart, actually?
- Well, you know what?
I'm channeling my inner granny.
- Yeah, I her grandfather
is Earl somebody.
11th in line for the throne.
- Seriously?
Check this.
- Ana?
- What's up?
- Do you want to go
see a movie tonight?
- Sure.
We could all use
the break, right?
- I mean like, go see
a movie, see a movie.
- What are you...?
Oh.
- Fuck, forsaken
cock fuckers, fuck!
- Good grief, Olivia.
- I cannot fucking believe this.
Can you fucking believe this?
- I cannot fucking believe it.
- I can't fucking
believe it, either.
More tea?
- Microsoft have a patch out.
- A patch?
- They're shutting
the worm down.
- Okay, so what
does that give us?
- A day Max.
- The meeting is on
Friday, the demo.
We'll get funding then.
- Not enough to pull
cycles on this scale.
- So?
- We need to do a final
test, a knock out.
- You're not suggesting...
- She is.
We need to be true revolutionaries
right out of the gate.
- She's right.
To guarantee investment
on this scale,
- we'll need to have...
- and we'd need to do it now.
Right now.
- Okay, I'll do it.
- Uh.
The world doesn't work like
that anymore, Lancelot.
- Well.
- Well, then.
- All systems operational.
Temperature's dropping, holding.
- Hydraulics one, up.
Hydraulics two, up.
Hydraulics three,
Liv, higher, higher.
Up.
- Diagnostics reading okay.
Still waiting for the
numbers to plateau.
- .272, .99.
Liv, the readings here,
they're inconsistent.
Cable one's overheating.
Switch to two and three.
- On my mark, engage phase two.
- Ana, hold still.
- Could this feel
anymore ominous?
At all?
- You don't have to
do this, you know?
- Yes, she does.
Now relax, exhale.
You're screwing
with the readings.
Nate?
- For the record, I'm
really, seriously scared.
- Don't be.
- This is all you.
- Picture the Nobel.
One last thing.
- What if I grow tentacles?
- Or testicles.
- A great big, Harry pair of...
- we phase matter.
We take matter and we pass
it through a wormhole.
- Unaltered, pass it unaltered.
- Your point?
- The numbers really are dropping.
- We should go.
- Just matter.
What if we're...
- What?
- Nothing, no.
Good luck.
- Nate?
You owe me a movie, cool guy.
- Good luck.
- Okay, and on three, two, one.
- Hi.
- Hi, I'm James. Do you have a moment?
- Sorry.
- No, don't be.
No, I'm kidding.
- You know this place?
- Look.
- They're using it for animal
testing, you know that?
- I'm sorry.
- Not today, okay?
- Okay, no worries, maybe next time.
- What's your name?
- Ana, yes.
- Ana, that's a lovely name.
I used to have a pet
rabbit called Ana.
Ana, you're in science, right?
- We don't really use animals.
- Oh, of course, of course.
- But you do...
- sorry, look.
I support what
you're doing, I do.
Just not today.
- Well, hello again.
How're you feeling?
- I shouldn't drink so much.
Can't remember shit.
I hope I didn't...
Good.
- So, we've pretty much
lost all of our capacity.
We're back to atoms
for the time being.
- Everything?
- That was quick.
- Was it really?
- Yeah, so basically
that thing is mothballed
for the moment.
- We do have computer models.
- We have.
Sorry.
We have it modeled, yes.
So we can run analytic
tests on the server.
- Until we get funding.
- Yes, until then.
- Everything went
okay though, right?
Nate?
- Yeah, of course.
Why do you ask?
- Okay, so what do we do next?
- What do we do?
Okay.
So firstly, how are those tests?
- Tests?
- You're the chemist.
You said you needed to
take samples, run tests.
- Memories, so many
wonderful memories.
Do you remember the video we did
from the photos of Loredo?
I found it upstairs.
- I will pack it as well.
- No, mom.
- Ay, let me pack it!
You can throw out
anything you don't want.
- That doesn't make sense,
it's more work for both of us.
Just throw it away,
or give it to charity.
- And the comic books?
- Just put them in the trunk.
- The trunk?
- I told you, everything
has to fit in a small trunk.
- But there's so many things!
- Well, that's the
point of a small trunk.
- You kept it, mom.
- Okay,
don't get antsy.
How are thing otherwise?
- They're...
Things are fine.
Just a bit of a
cold, but I'm okay.
- Don't work too hard.
I miss you.
- Hello?
Okay, okay then.
Just please, leave
my stuff and go.
Please leave my work!
For fuck's sake!
Hey!
Who are you?
I don't need to call the police,
I just want my stuff.
It's just my work.
It's worthless to you.
Please.
Good.
- Ana, are you okay?
Your voicemail had me worried.
It must be late there.
- My voicemail?
I...
My room's been broken into.
They took my laptop
and some other stuff.
- Did you lose much work?
- Well, it's backed
up at the lab.
It's also photos, memories.
- I found something last
night I'm going to send you.
It'll cheer you up.
- Okay.
- I love you, baby.
- Don't worry, mom,
I'll call them.
I love you, too.
So I can't even report my card
stolen, that's ridiculous!
I don't know!
It's just...
Yes.
Okay.
My passport.
Can I take a name and
a reference number?
Okay, Jim.
I'll do it tomorrow.
Yes.
No.
Thank you.
But why aren't you
taking this seriously?
Someone stole our work.
- Look, it's not like they'll
make sense of anything.
And you don't remember
what happened...
- no, that's what I'm saying!
After the experiment, nothing!
I can't remember!
I mean, was I attacked
on my way home?
'Cause my room is trashed,
my head hurts all the time,
- and I've been...
- hey, hey.
Don't worry.
- I'm not worried.
I just want to
know what happened.
No, something went wrong
with the experiment.
- Nothing went wrong.
You'll have forgotten
all about it tomorrow.
- Listen, it's really
not such a big deal.
- Nate, listen to yourself.
You're being weird.
My passport, bank
cards, all my work.
Something's not right.
- Ah, cock bollocks.
- Here we go.
- So what's going on?
- Check your
email, we all got it.
I needed to think about it...
- before you
discuss with us, you mean?
- Exactly.
- Check your email.
- Someone stole my computer.
- So they did.
- Wow.
- Yeah.
- Utterly untraceable
were your exact words.
- They've traced
it to the university.
This is a big place.
- Liv, we don't...
- This is a big place.
- Look, someone is
gonna come and ask questions.
How well do you think
that's gonna go, Olivia?
- I'm the one who let her out.
- Just saying.
- What's GCHQ, anyway?
- What's wrong with you?
- Government communications HQ.
They deal with cyber terrorism.
- How worried should we be?
- Cyber terrorism?
- I don't see how it
could be traced directly to us,
unless we do something
really stupid of course.
- Nate, how many
days have passed?
Since the experiment?
It's a simple question, I
can go check for myself.
- Will you stop that,
it's getting on my nerves.
- Two weeks, I think.
- You think.
Okay, thanks for your help.
- What's that?
- A notebook.
Did I tell you I'm not
remembering things?
- You were attack, mugged.
- Thanks, I'll write that down.
It's good that you
both seem so concerned.
- We are.
- I really am.
Why do you think
- we're working so hard?
- Doing what?
- Why won't you let me help?
- Help?
Yes, that'd be great.
So, how're the tests?
- What tests?
See, that's what I mean.
I can't remember.
- You needed to
take samples to see
- if the wormhole...
- come on.
You're saying I didn't
do that already?
Why is this locked?
It's never locked.
- Don't you have the keys?
- What keys?
I have been in this
room all semester.
- There are no keys.
- Okay, relax.
I'll ask maintenance.
- You know, I dreamed
about this room last night.
- Someone must've
locked it, I'll check.
- Who else has been in here?
They have my laptop.
Maybe they're
after the project...
- we're here all the time.
Nobody's after our
project, don't be paranoid.
- My project.
- Yes, Ana, your project.
Are you okay?
You didn't eat lunch.
Get some rest.
I'll put the tests into incubate
and we'll go over them
in the morning, okay?
- Nate.
- Don't antagonize her, okay?
- She winds me up.
- She's fragile, but
she's still smart.
We don't want her
messing this up, alright?
- Hey, where did you get that?
Where did you get that mask?
- Where did you buy it?
- Let go of me, murderer.
- Oh, hi, hello.
- Sorry.
- Don't be.
Joining us today?
- I need to go home.
- Actually, those ape masks, who has...
- Ana.
Ana, we know.
- How do you know my name?
- We know what you're doing
in there, your experiment.
You have two options.
- You do the right thing...
- or what?
I'm sorry, are you
threatening me?
Do you want me to
call the police?
- Be my guest.
- Hey, hey!
- They're leaving
via the back window, three.
Any sign of them?
- Negative, it's empty.
I'll head up a floor.
- Hello?
Hello?
- Ana, hi.
How're you feeling?
- How do you know where I am?
- Okay.
How would I know where you are?
You aren't at home?
- I'm out, I'm not
feeling so good.
- Your head still hurting?
- My head?
It's okay.
Nate, I need to talk to you.
- Something's not...
- I know, that's why I called.
Look, I'm in London
tomorrow with the team.
But you want to go grab
dinner when I get back?
- With Liv?
- No, just you and me
tomorrow at the Sushi place.
Nine, I'll say.
- Ana, are you...
- yes, I said yes.
- Right it down, okay?
There's a pen by the mouse cage.
- You should eat.
You look awful.
Not like that, but...
I don't understand
why you're not eating.
- What's happening?
- What do you mean?
- You know what I mean, Nate.
What's happening?
- You tell me.
- Don't do that.
Don't make this
difficult for me.
- Don't be weird.
Look, I'm not trying to make
anything difficult for anyone.
- Then what's happening?
- And I want you to tell me.
What's wrong?
What've have you to
be paranoid about?
- It's not paranoia, Nate.
There's something
faulty with my memory.
- You were hit.
- Then I should see a doctor.
No.
It has to do with the wormhole.
- You're seeing a doctor.
You've got an MRI
scan in two weeks.
- Do I now?
See, that's what I mean.
I'm having trouble remembering
things, recent things.
- Well, we tested for that
with the mice and with the cat.
- I don't know what it is.
And you guys, I mean.
- You're not helping.
- Ana.
- What?
- You've told us this
before, all of it.
Told us.
Look, Ana, I need you
to stop investigating.
The detective stuff,
it's dangerous.
I mean, with the government
agency and the worm and...
They're sending
someone to investigate.
Ana, I need you to
trust me on this.
Do you remember two summers ago,
we went climbing in the quarry
with the ropes and stuff?
Remember how I got stuck?
Like, really stuck?
And I was scared.
I think I even cried a little.
- You cried a lot, Nate.
I didn't know grown men
could cry like that.
- I was scared.
But you talked me through
it, you got me down.
I trusted you.
And I trusted that you wouldn't
tell anyone else, either.
- I never did.
Except my mom.
- You told your mom?
- Sure.
I mean, she's my mom.
She thinks you're cute.
- So I need you to trust me.
Stop the investigation.
Okay, that's good.
But I need you to write it down.
Write it down.
Stop the investigation,
trust Nate, trust Liv.
Ana, please.
- If I ask you to
kiss me right now,
what would you do?
- Why aren't you eating?
You really should eat.
- I am exhausted.
- Yep.
Yeah, me too.
Hey, look, your silk
worm is still alive.
I think he's trying
to make a nest.
- It's called a cocoon, Nathan.
- Your only friend
in the whole world.
You okay?
- Looking for something?
- Any idea what this means?
- No idea.
- What does is mean?
- You wrote it, sister.
It's a prime number,
if that helps.
- Where's my camcorder?
- My place.
I took it to digitize
the experiments.
- Yep, you said
he should take it.
- Did I really?
- Mhmm.
- Can you bring it back?
It'll help to see
what we've been up to.
- Sure.
- What are you working on?
- I'm trying to
streamline the code, Ana.
- So?
- So we can operate
the generator again
without all those illegally
acquired processors.
Happy?
- Why don't you call your mom?
How is she, anyway?
- How did her move go?
- My mother?
Why, is she involved in this?
- Oh, my god.
- Look, you want me out of here.
I get it.
Why mention my mother?
What is going on?
I dream about this
door, I dream about it!
- Hey, you guys
better come join us.
The vice chancellor's here.
- So, as I was saying,
it infected millions, hundreds
of millions of computers.
Apparently.
And it's been traced
to our university,
to this department,
ladies and gentlemen,
from an IP address
in this building.
Well done.
You've actually achieved
something of significance.
This is Mr.
Stovington from GCHQ.
He'll be questioning
everyone in the department.
Do cooperate.
And you're welcome to have
a member of faculty present,
should you wish.
- Ana!
Ana.
Jesus, get a grip.
- Okay, so this detective guy.
Tell me again just how
we don't end up in jail.
- She's not gonna stand
up to questioning.
- She'll be fine,
won't you, Ana?
- Where are the patents?
- The what where?
- The patents.
You're stealing my project.
- Excuse me?
Where are the filing documents?
- In whose name are they?
- They're in your name.
- Then where are they?
- With my father's solicitor.
- What did you do to me?
- I warned you.
- Ana, Liv and I
are trying to help.
- No!
- What did we do to her?
- Yeah.
- Ana.
- You said something
about matter, about how
the wormhole moving matter.
What was that about?
- I don't remember.
- No, you do.
You said, "the wormhole,
it just sends matter."
- Yeah, but...
- Go home, just calm down.
- But what if there's
something else?
If we're more than just matter?
What if there's a part of
me that doesn't have mass?
If I went through but...
But my soul was left behind.
- Uh, I'm not sure
I can take this.
- Okay, look, you need
to listen to yourself.
You just accused us of
trying to steal your project,
and now you're talking
about your soul.
- You're fucking crazy.
- Liv, shut up.
Okay.
Look, Ana, we're trying to help.
We do care.
Ana, Ana!
Shit.
- Ana!
Twice in one day, lucky me.
- Everything okay?
- Hey.
Mom, look.
- Have I been...
- acting a bit strange?
Yes, you have.
- Say again?
- No, this morning.
Did we talk already today?
- Ana, are you sure you're...
- What password?
- I don't know.
You said I shouldn't talk to
you unless you say a password.
- What was the password?
- Ana.
- Mom.
- Is that really you?
- Of course.
Mom, hey.
- You said that
you'd say a word,
that I shouldn't trust
you unless you say...
- you're my mom.
I'm not giving you a
password to talk to you.
Just don't listen to me
if I talk to you about...
- Ana.
I have to go.
There's someone at the door.
Talk to me when
you're feeling better.
- Nate, look, I'm really sorry.
Oh, god, sorry.
- I thought you were someone else.
- No, it's okay.
- Don't worry.
- Sorry.
What are you...?
- Neurological damage,
just doing some research.
- Well, good luck.
- Thanks.
- Excuse me, can I
ask you something?
- Yeah, I have a boyfriend.
- Oh, god no, don't worry.
I'm just trying to
work something out.
Does human memory have mass?
I mean, if you could
wipe a person's memories,
would their brain weigh less?
Weird one, I know.
- It's just...
- no, no.
Um, it's an
interesting question.
You know, I have no idea.
Have you tried Google?
- It just want to
sell me USB sticks.
- Well, how do they work?
Do they weigh more
when they're full?
- No, I wouldn't
imagine, anyway.
They're just zeros and ones.
- I think the human memory
works much the same.
It's electricity, ons and offs.
Like an empty battery
has the same...
- has the same
mass as a full one.
I know about batteries.
So memory is electricity,
but electricity is electrons
and electrons have mass.
Thanks.
One last thing.
Do you think we're
more than our memories?
I mean, we're born with none
and die with a lifetime's worth.
So when we talk about
the idea of a soul,
maybe we're just
talking about...
Sorry, you're busy.
Thanks, anyway.
- Good luck with your work.
- Thank you.
- Someone with a key?
Yeah, I'll hold.
- Oh, yeah.
- They're asking everyone.
Someone broke in over
at the chemistry lab.
Probably some drugs, then.
- These protestors are horrid.
They shouldn't allowed to
harass people like that.
- I know, right?
- This is Oxford.
- Tracy said her rep said they'll
be arresting someone today
for the Internet thing.
- Ana, hi. You um...
- Don't.
I don't trust you.
I don't believe you,
so just don't, okay?
- You heard about the break in?
- I did, actually.
- A protester, they
think, a week ago.
Caught on CCTV, though they
can't make out the face.
- Couldn't they?
- You muppet.
Why the hell are you breaking...
- something's very wrong
with me, you know this.
- Yes, something is.
- Because of that.
- It's complicated.
- I'm sure it is.
- It's not what you think.
- What do I think, Nate?
Tell me.
Look, I'm like a crazy person.
So whatever you did
to me, well done.
- It worked.
- Yeah.
Ana, there is something
wrong with you,
- but we don't know how...
- you're lying.
You want the project,
but it's my project.
It's mine, and I'm
closing it down.
- Ana, what have you done?
- Hello, somebody
call maintenance?
- Yes, we need the keys
for the storage room.
Can you open it?
- Ana.
- Nathan.
- I gave you the key
for this already.
You said you would
bring it right back.
- No, I don't think it was...
- that's right, darlin'.
We were stood right here.
- Look, can you open the door?
- Not without the key and
if you've lost the only one,
I'll have to fetch
a member of faculty.
- That won't be necessary.
We'll find it.
What the hell are you doing?
Are you nuts?
We broke the law!
There's police everywhere,
and you want to bring some,
some pissant farm
hand down here.
And what if he goes to the VC?
And the VC goes, gee, heck.
You know, all this kooky
stuff and the government
are investigating us because
for some damn worm virus...
- Liv!
- Fuck you,
you know that I'm brain damaged
and none of you have
done anything to help!
- You're not brain damaged, Ana.
- Did I not tell you to shut up?
Fuck you both.
- Sir, she's here.
- Hello, Ms. Carter.
- Shouldn't I have a lawyer?
Am I being arrested?
- Heavens, no.
No, we simply wish to
ask you some questions.
I mean, you are perfectly entitled
to have a lawyer present.
But in that case, well,
then we'd have to travel
all the way across town
and fill in lots and lots
of paper work, and so on,
and so forth.
I mean, it really is quite dull.
Come.
Please.
Would you like a peanut?
I have this theory that you
can always tell if a man...
Oh, well in your case a woman,
is guilty based
on how they react
when the interrogation
officer offers them a peanut.
- No, thank you.
- No?
Sure?
Suit yourself.
So.
- So?
- So what do you think?
- About what?
- Well, do you think you passed
my guilty peanut test or not?
I'm only messing.
I do apologize.
However, you would be
amazed the amount of men
I've had admit to
murdering their own parents
by offering them a peanut.
Would you like a peanut?
"Oh, I killed my mother!"
I mean, it's...
It's like a magic trick.
Anyway.
To business.
- Look, mister.
I'm sorry, I'm really busy.
- Yes, I know.
You're a hard one to pin
down, keep very strange hours.
I mean, most students
do, but you, you're...
- can we do this another time?
- I'm not really...
- have a look at this.
Tell me if you recognize it.
- What is this?
- I'll be honest with you.
We're not looking for
the worm's author.
We know you wrote it,
but what we don't
know is what it does.
Come now.
What, you thought you'd
get, oh, 800 million people
to do your homework and
it would stay a secret?
- Look, I've been
unwell, alright?
But I have no idea
what I'm looking at.
You know I'm a chemist,
not a programmer.
- All we want to know
is what it is, miss Carter.
Anarchy?
Clogging up the system?
- Are you a part of that?
- I have no idea.
- Anarchy?
- Well, your friends...
- they're not my
friends, are they?
Why don't you ask them.
- We have gathered
here today for one reason,
and one reason only.
- Over 18%
of students are scientists.
We have murder on our hands
if we let this stuff go ahead.
- Ana!
Ana, everybody.
This is Ana we were
telling you all about.
- She's American.
- Is she?
- She is.
- Well, that makes sense.
- Decided not to join
us in the end, then?
- Clearly not, though we did
give you every chance to.
- We did, we tried.
- What is this?
- So, what do we have here?
Half a dozen lab mice?
- Only mice.
Then rabbits.
But you've left this
section blank, Ana.
What were you doing to them?
- What are you doing
to them, Ana, in there?
- Witnesses said they
saw you bring a cat in.
But where's the paperwork, Ana?
- Where, indeed?
- A pet.
That's not legal, Ana.
- That's not legal at all.
You should see what
they built in there.
- Listen.
- Should we?
Should we see her lab?
- No!
- We have everything
we need, Ana!
- We're shutting you down.
- Shut her down!
Shut her down!
- Shut her down! Shut her down!
- Aw!
We're only joking, Ana!
- Wah-wah.
- My notes.
What's wrong with me?
Hi, I think I left
something here last time.
- Oh, well come in, come in.
Would you like some tea?
- I would love some tea.
- Ana!
- Hey, look, are you okay?
- Peachy.
- Where are you?
Can you come back to the lab?
- All I wanted was for you
to explain what was going on.
- We explained
it to you so many times.
Ana, you just keep forgetting.
Look, look, I'm sorry.
Can you just come
back to the lab?
- Ana?
- Goodbye, Nathan.
- Yes, she does!
Now relax, exhale.
You're screwing
with the readings.
- Nate.
- We phase matter.
We take matter and
we pass it through...
- unaltered, pass it unaltered.
- Your point?
Numbers really are
dropping, we have to go!
- Just matter, right?
- We're...
- What?
- Nothing, no.
- Nate?
You owe me a movie, cool guy.
- Okay.
And on three, two, one.
- 271 apparently successful.
Readings inconclusive,
couldn't map the subsets.
The wormhole stays
open too long.
Gravitational distortion,
needs to close instantaneously
to do a wormhole.
Guys, we have a problem.
Two, one.
- Ana, what are you doing here?
- I'm...
- I mean, what are you doing here?
- It's my room.
- How did you know I was here?
- It's my room, I
was coming home.
- You were at the lab.
You were at the lab, how
did you know I was here?
- Ana, listen...
- how did you know I was here?!
- Jesus.
- Look, you told me.
You told me you were here.
- You're sleeping with Liv,
which I don't give a fuck about.
But Nate, you're not stupid.
You must know how
much that hurts me.
I thought you and me, we had...
- forget about Liv, please!
Look, and you're the one
going through my underwear.
So just, enough.
We never realized how badly
this was affecting you.
- Affecting, Nate?
- Affecting?
I'm losing my mind!
I don't eat, I don't drink.
My dreams are insane.
I have no memories, I have
to make notes all the time.
- It's...
- you can have them back.
- I don't want them back!
Am I insane?
I do things behind
my own back and...
- please, just put that down.
Come to the lab.
- We can explain it there.
- Explain now.
- No.
No, you won't remember.
Come to the lab.
Liv has rewritten the algorithm.
- What is happening to me, Nate?
What is that?
What is that?!
Why don't I eat?
Why don't I remember?
Answer it.
- Don't threaten me.
I'm trying to help.
- Answer the phone.
You want me to trust you?
- Okay.
Hello.
No, no, I'm with her now.
- Who is it?
Who is it?
- This is
Ana Carter, U.S. citizen.
This is Ana Carter.
Ana Carter, Ana
Carter, Ana Carter...
Something's not right.
- Everything will change.
People, we're going to be gods.
- It doesn't
look like I thought it would.
- It that really you?
- Why don't you call your mom?
How is she, anyway?
How did her move go?
- Want to see a magic trick?
Want to see a magic trick?
- You thought
you'd get 800 million people
to help you do your homework
and it would stay a secret?
I'm losing my mind!
Losing my mind!
- Is that really you?
- Do you want to
go see a movie tonight?
We'll go see a movie.
- You're the chemist.
Said you needed to take
samples, run tests.
- I found something last night,
it'll cheer you up.
- Nobody's after our project.
- To the moon, to the moon.
To the vault of a bank.
Anywhere.
- Ana, thank fuck.
- Where's Nate?
- Come inside.
- I shot him.
- I need help.
- What are you doing?
You didn't shoot anyone.
- You need to help me, okay?
I've lost my soul.
- Do I...
Ah, yes!
I did the peanut routine
with you earlier, didn't I?
Sorry about that.
- It's Carter, miss Carter.
- Yes, yes.
- Look, I don't know why
I do that shit, but, uh,
let's get you cleaned up.
- High as a kite.
- No, it's a wormhole.
And they slept together!
- You in some sort of trouble?
- No trouble, officer.
- She's fine, aren't you?
- I've lost my soul.
- I saw it on the video.
- Okay, yep.
Come on, let's get you inside.
- No!
It was you!
- You did this to me!
- You fucking muppet.
- Come on.
- No!
- Ana, I'm trying to help.
Okay?
Shit.
Your level of gratitude
leaves a little something
to be desired.
Nate, I found her in the crowd.
Christ, what did she do to you?
- I've lost my mind.
- You haven't.
- Nate, I have.
I have.
I'm seeing things
that cannot be real.
I've hurt myself.
I hurt you.
- We understand what happened.
- Did you see the video?
- Mhmm.
- What was that?
- Was that my soul?
- Don't, okay?
That's not science,
and it doesn't help.
- You remember the experiment.
- Yes, I remember
the experiment.
- We needed readings.
- So we could run it
as a computer model.
But the wormhole was open
too long, creating a vacuum.
- Your generator
creates wormholes.
Wormhole theory takes the
fabric of space and time
and it folds it
creating a path here.
- We, your machine,
the algorithm,
induces an event
horizon at the out node.
- A mathematical black hole
pulling the subject through.
- So it was open
too long and...?
- And the gravity field
distorted the readings.
Our numbers were
all over the chart.
- You remember the first
time you went through.
Afterwards, we
decided, all of us,
that we had to
get those numbers.
- The first time?
- We had to find a way
to shut it off the
nanosecond you were through.
- We had to...
Yes, the worm's
numbers were dropping.
So we had to make
sure it snapped shut
the moment my mass was through.
You used the scale sensor to
automatically cut the generator
the moment it had
weight applied to it.
- It was your idea.
- So, we ran it again.
I went through a second time.
But then...
After that I can't...
What happened?
- Three, two, one.
- 271 apparently successful.
- What?
- Keep watching.
The wormhole stays
open too long.
Guys, we have a problem.
Okay, so there's the out node
with the scale sensor cutoff.
Okay, we ready?
- Are we not
moving a little fast here?
- It's fine, I'm fine,
and we've done this once.
- Yeah, and the
cycles are dropping.
We have minutes, seconds, even.
It's really now or never.
- Come on, we need this.
It's fine.
- Okay, and on three, two, one.
- Liv!
- Shit.
You alright?
What the fuck?
- No, no, no, no, no.
What am I?
- Ana.
- Am I a clone?
- Tell me what that is?
- Okay, please, not again.
- We can show you.
- What happened?
- Relax, Ana!
- Just listen to us, please!
- Tell me!
- Every time!
Every time.
- Jesus, you're not a clone!
- I am, I saw!
There were two of them!
- You're a chemist,
you dumb shit!
All those samples you took!
- Liv, she doesn't remember.
- No.
Well, there's the microscope.
Show her.
Tell you girlfriend to
write it down this time!
Jesus, you fucking shot at me.
- Don't.
- You don't need to.
- So?
- Increase the resolution.
- It's not working properly.
- Oh, it is.
- There's nothing
here, there's no...
- It's complicated.
- Woops, you're an anomaly.
A quantum fucking mistake.
- Liv, don't make
any harder than it is.
- No?
I am sick of her
thinking I'm the bad guy.
I've hardly slept the last
month trying to figure it out!
And the number of times, daily,
that this retard comes in
and shoots at me!
Where the hell did she
get a gun from, anyway?
- You're light, Ana.
When we fold space and we pull
you across the event horizon,
we're pulling you faster
than the speed of light.
That's how a wormhole works.
You're the light
that got left behind.
- That's not possible.
I'm more than just a copy.
I think.
I mean, I'm thinking right now.
I have emotions.
I am.
- We don't understand
it, either.
You're light.
You have photonic weight.
You have a radiation signature.
You do exist.
- I'm just not real.
- Not in the normal sense.
It's why you're not making
memories, or eating, or drinking.
- It's why your dreams are so...
- my dreams.
My dreams are vivid.
Like, like I'm looking
through someone else's...
Tell me.
I know what happens next.
- Hey.
Sorry I pushed you in the alley.
That whole day was just...
I was so scared.
You don't remember
though, do you?
- And her?
- Well, she has mass.
She...
She exists.
She's the real Ana.
- No.
Bullshit, don't say that!
How can I not be?
- This is really
hard for me, too.
I feel hollow, like
I'm missing something.
- Yeah, like a soul?
- Hey, I eat, I walk
around everyday.
I remember what I do.
I remember what you do.
I was pulled through.
I'm real.
- It'll be alright,
and we're gonna be there.
- I know.
- Just don't be sad, okay?
This'll work out.
The algorithm's being
rewritten, and I'll talk to her.
- To me, you mean.
- Just for the
moment, can we not...?
- So, what happened?
You two?
What, just like that?
- Ana, I'm crazy about you.
I have been for so long.
- Why her, then?
- Why not me?
- Because you're not real.
- We can fix it.
- We open up the wormhole again.
- I've rewritten the code so
that it's no longer defined
by volume but by mass.
You have no mass, we
can send you through.
- Send me where?
- You won't go anywhere.
Nowhere, essentially.
It's...
It's like smashing a mirror.
Your reflection
doesn't go anywhere,
it's just...
Gone.
- You want to kill me.
- You're not alive to kill.
You're my reflection.
You'll open your
eyes and be here.
- I am real, I exist!
Oh, my god!
I exist, I don't want to die!
- Mom?
- Hi, it's me.
- I just got your...
- mom, I love you so much.
I just don't tell
you this enough.
- Oh, baby, don't be silly.
I love you, too.
Are you okay?
Do you remember?
I remember.
Memories are wonderful.
Did you get my package?
Do you remember playing
the piano with me?
- Yes.
How can I not be real if
I remember these things?
- Why?
- So we can have a record of it,
so we can show Papi.
It helps him to remember.
Now, are you ready?
Like we practiced, okay?
- Like that?
- Si, exactly like that.
Now don't stop, okay, Annie?
- Mom, sorry.
I'm just listening
to it right now.
I'll call you tomorrow, okay?
Love you.
- Mommy!
Mommy, I love you!
I love you so much!
Mommy!
What about the things I've done?
What about my memories,
the stuff that makes me me!
- They're mine, not yours.
All those things you've
done, they're here.
Can't I just stay here?
Please, I can sleep in there.
Just give me one last...
- you won't remember this.
- We've tried it before.
- We kept you here at first.
- Seemed safe.
- But you would
forget everything.
- Everything.
- It was horrible.
You hurt yourself.
- You hurt us.
- We couldn't get anything done.
- It was easier
with you out there.
- It was just...
- Awful for you, I know.
I felt it everyday.
You okay?
- No, not really.
- I know.
- Yeah, you probably do.
I'm scared.
- What?
- So.
- Yeah.
- Look at us,
sitting here like
two normal people.
I feel like I should
say something profound.
- You know, if I
were in your place...
If I were you,
I don't know if I could do this.
I don't think I could.
- Yeah, you could.
Thank you.
You're an asshole and if
I think that, so does she.
Go on, then.
Hit me.
- Three, two, one.
- Salud.
- And the project?
- We shut it down.
- No, why?
- I'm with Ana, I mean...
- how can we stop progress?
It's out there now,
we know it's possible.
- Someone else will discover it.
- And you think it should be us?
- Even after what we just...
- well, because of that, yes!
Do we outlaw cars
because people crash?
Or electricity because
it electrocutes?
I have the MRI on Thursday,
that'll give us some closure.
Then we press ahead.
It's called progress.
Did we really imagine
there weren't gonna
be any teething issues?
- And the worm?
The investigation?
- I can hack the
blame onto anyone,
I just need someone
with a motive.
- We still have a million
more tests to run, true.
But we need to move forward.
And to move forward,
we need money, funding.
Now you said that the
meetings were back on.
- Yeah, but...
- Good, good.
Now, then.
Do you remember all the cool
shit we said we were gonna do?
Watch.
Everything will change.
Guys, pay attention.
Can we get something to eat?
I'm starving.
Yeah?
Come on.
- Wow, that was amazing.
Wasn't it?
What a clever sticks you are.
- I did okay?
- You were brilliant.
Now, this is the best part.
We can go back and listen to
it again, and again if we want.
- Can I give it to Papi?
- Sure you can.
When he comes back,
you can do anything.
Now, press that to turn it off.